Jude?
Jude. I'm home.
Turn off the video games.
Jude.
Gotcha!
Shit!
Another prank?
Why do you have to keep doing this?
I got you good, didn't 1?
You think you're funny, huh?
Hmm.
Mmm. Okay. Okay.
Saved by your dad.
- Hi.
- Dad.
What's up, mate?
You being the big man of the house
and taking care of your mum?
More like scaring his old mom.
I used the shoe trick.
The shoe trick.
Now, let me see.
No, I think you must be mistaking me
with someone else, mate.
Real sneaky, you two.
I can't stay long, love.
I've golia lake some clients out
for dinner.
But I just wanted fo check in
on my two favorite people,
and let you know that I miss you both
and I love you guys so much.
- Love you, dad.
- Bye, kiddo.
Later!
You know, it's the third time this week
you've been late.
I know, I know.
I've just got lo finish these deadlines,
then I'm done. I promise.
When I get back,
maybe I can find a way
to make it up fo you.
Well, Friday night,
we do have the nanny.
Oh, Well, then I will see you
on Friday night, lady.
If you're lucky.
- Night.
- Good night, love.
Were you really scared, mom?
I was.
But next time,
let's get your dad.
Okay.
Looks like Mr. brown
could use a cuddle.
- Mom.
- Hmm.
I'm too old to still sleep
with a Teddy bear.
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
Good night.
Good night, mom.
Jude?
If you're trying to scare me again,
it's not funny.
Okay.
Mom!
What are you doing?
Mom, don't!
No! No!
Jude!
Mommy!
I thought we could take a look
at some of those toys today.
Or perhaps there's something
you'd like to talk about?
You don't like coming here
very much, do you?
But you do understand
why you're here?
You know, Jude,
If you'd like to go,
all you need to do is to say,
"I'd like to go now."
Five months isn't an unusual time
for this kind of selective mutism.
I've seen children stop talking
for much longer
from much less severe trauma.
Encourage him to communicate,
but try not to force it.
It has to come from him.
The more we force things,
the more he's gonna pull back.
And how are the two of you holding up?
We're good, yeah.
As well as we can be.
We're really just trying to focus
on Jude's recovery right now.
Well, I commend your dedication.
But Jude is looking to you now.
And if you're not getting better,
he won't get better.
Thank you.
Another headache?
It's not that bad.
I thought the doctor
had some good things to say.
Yeah.
I think Jude is a little better.
No. I meant, actually,
about us healing too.
Well...
I'm fine, really.
You never leave the house.
You have nightmares
every night...
And you don't even let me touch you.
I'm not having this conversation again.
We've never had this conversation.
You've never talked about
what happened or how you feel.
What if we went away?
Out of the city,
some place quiet.
You're already homeschooling Jude.
I can work wherever.
I think it would be a good chance
for us to have a fresh start.
I'll think about it.
What is it, sweetheart?
Liza!
Liza, be quiet!
Liza.
Liza. Liza.
It's okay.
You're all right.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
It's okay.
I can't do this anymore.
Hiya! I'm Pamela.
Oh, I'm glad you found it.
Shall I show you the house?
And what's this little man's name?
Jude.
He's a little shy.
Oh, well, I bet we'll be
best of friends in no time.
This used to be a guesthouse
of a much larger property.
But after the owner of
the manor house passed away,
some city man, no offense,
came and scooped it up.
I think he was gonna restore it, but I
imagine the job got too much for him.
Lucky for you folks, though.
Some time in the countryside.
It's perfect.
I'll give you a little tour if you like.
No. I think we can handle it from here.
Oh. All right.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
Cheers. Bye-bye.
So, what do you think?
It's beautiful.
Yeah?
You sure? Yes.
And what about you,
big boss?
All right.
I vote we try a little...
Nature exploration!
- Isn't it beautiful?
- Yeah, it's so quiet.
Look at the sun.
Smell the air.
That's fresh air.
I bet we'll see loads of rabbits
come spring.
Maybe even some deer, huh?
Yeah.
Watch your step, mate.
It's slippery.
What's that?
That must be the main house.
Let's check it out.
Look at that.
Wow. Now that is what
I call a house. Come here.
Come on, Jude.
Jude.
Wow.
This place must've been
quite something back in the day.
"Glennview estate."
Jude, come play with us.
Jude.
Come here, Jude.
Over here.
Jude.
Come over here.
Now, Jude.
We'll have to look it up.
Old house like this
probably got some real history to it.
Sean.
Jude, Jude.
Help me, Jude.
Jude, Jude, Jude.
Yes, Jude.
Yeah, forget the guesthouse.
I'm moving in here.
What do you say, Jude?
Jude?
- Jude!
- Jude?
Jude!
Mate, don't run off like that, please.
You can't run off like that,
not out here.
What's that?
Did you just find that?
Can I take a look?
Oh, my goodness.
It's filthy. Look at it.
Whereabouts did you find it?
Do you wanna keep it?
Okay.
Let's get it cleaned up first.
All right. Can't wait to have
this guy in the house.
Can I see?
"Rules."
Huh.
I bet you have a story to tell.
Looks like he wants a friend.
He looks like he was broken before...
And put back together again.
Okay, let's go to bed now.
Hmm?
Come on, mate.
You sure you got everything
you need there, little fella? Yeah?
You just make yourself at home.
Put your feet up.
There's nice,
Cold beer in the fridge.
I could use some of those pj's.
You dressed him yourself.
That sounds lovely.
Are you hungry?
Okay.
I'll make pancakes.
I guess it's about time for me
to start my morning commute
all the way down the hallway.
I really hope there's no traffic, guys.
You wanna stop by the office
for lunch today?
Did I mention that I was
just down the hallway?
I'll try to sneak by.
Goodbye, judester. Mwah.
Goodbye...
Did we come up with a name for him yet?
"Brahms." wow.
Like the composer?
That's quite the name.
How'd you come up with that?
Oh, he told you.
Oh, right, yeah.
Well, of course, he did.
Silly me.
All right.
Bye, gang.
Goodbye, brahms.
Well, what should we start with today,
math or history?
Okay.
Over here.
Wait up!
Right here.
This way.
Jude!
I told you not to run off like that.
This is where you found him?
Oz, get in here.
This is private property.
I'm sorry. We're staying
at the guesthouse.
We were just on a walk.
I didn't know.
Of course you didn't.
You're the new family.
Sorry, I get a lot of people
snooping around up here.
I'm Joseph. Joe.
Um, I tend the grounds around here.
Part guard, part gardener.
This is oz.
I'm Liza.
And this is Jude.
We can put the doll back.
Do you want us...
No, no, no.
Keep it.
No one's gonna miss it out here.
Just me and oz these days.
Unless, of course,
you'd like to put it back?
He's a little quiet.
Oh, don't worry about that.
Not much of a talker meself.
People think I'm crazy
for living out here on my own,
but I'm more sane than any of them.
The real crazy is living in the city,
packed together like a bunch of cattle.
Thank you, but no,
thank you.
You didn't really have to
walk us all the way back.
Oh, I don't mind.
We're neighbors now.
I suppose I'll be seeing
quite a bit of you.
Hey there.
That's a healthy-looking 12 Gauge.
Or a 12 bore.
I was worried about you.
This is Joseph.
Joseph, this is my husband, Sean.
- Hiya.
- Joseph...
I tend the grounds round here.
Keep the troublemakers out.
Caught these two red-handed.
Yeah, these two are trouble,
all right.
Well, thanks for escorting them back.
Right. I'll be off, then.
Let me know if you need anything, yeah?
Yeah. Nice meeting you.
Pleasure was all mine.
See you soon, little fella.
Bringing home the local strays
already, huh?
Look, he insisted on
walking us all the way home.
Come on, oz.
Come on.
Nice of him,
I guess.
Who the hell buries a doll
in the woods like that?
Maybe some weird little kid
put it there.
I don't know, sweetheart.
Yeah, but you weren't there.
You didn't see it.
His entire wardrobe,
in this...
Coffin thing.
Okay.
So, what do you wanna do?
You wanna take
the doll away from him?
Yes.
No.
I don't know.
I just think it's all a little bit...
Creepy.
I really don't think it's the doll
that's the problem here.
What does that mean?
Nothing. Let's just
finish the dishes, yeah?
I've got some work to do
before we go to sleep.
No, I wanna hear
what you were about to say.
What's the problem?
Sometimes I feel like you use Jude...
To avoid talking about
what happened to you.
And I don't think that's healthy
for either of you.
Mommy!
You know,
I nearly died...
In some random,
senseless burglary.
And I'm actually aware of that
every single day of my life.
Yes, but that's over now.
Lj...
Dogs bark.
You didn't like the dog?
The dog.
Dogs bark.
I know what you mean.
He was kind of scary.
Liza, I'm sorry.
Holy shit.
Should we just leave him alone?
Do you wanna open the door?
No, I wanna go in.
I wanna see if he'll talk to us.
Okay. Let's go.
So, all this is yours?
Hey, sweetheart.
We were just outside,
and we thought we heard you talking.
Were you talking to brahms?
Great.
So, what were you guys talking about?
Oh, the dog from this morning.
Did he scare you?
"Brahms doesn't like him." Oh.
Well, that's...
That's great.
We'll let you get back to brahms.
Good night.
Thinking about watching a movie,
if you're interested.
Oh, yeah.
Sure.
I guess we're keeping that doll.
Are you kidding?
I love that creepy thing.
Liza, it's okay. Honey, it's okay.
Look at me.
It was just a dream.
It's fine. You're okay.
Jude.
Jude, I'm sorry.
He's mine!
You okay?
Another nightmare?
Where's Jude?
He slept in his room, love.
This is the first time
he's slept in his own bed.
Come on.
Let's go back to bed.
Here you go.
Do you want two, yeah?
Does brahms want two?
Hey, good morning.
You're up.
I let you lie in.
It seemed like you could use it.
Thank you.
Cooked up a little full english.
Here you go, love.
What's this?
Oh. That. Yes.
Well, apparently,
brahms is handing down rules now,
including he'd like his own food.
Oh, dear.
What happened to Mr. brown?
Jude, buddy,
did you do this?
Come on, mate.
It's not very nice
to blame him now, is it?
Look, we're not mad at you.
But this is no way to treat your things.
And it's never okay to lie.
So, did you cut up Mr. brown?
Okay. Then why don't you go to your room
and finish your homework there?
And then when you're ready to tell me
what happened, you can come out.
You can leave the doll here.
Jude.
You heard your mum.
Leave the doll, please.
Maybe it's a good thing.
He's getting his anger out.
It's pretty violent.
Really?
That wasn't funny.
You're supposed to stay in this room,
and not come out again
until you're ready to apologize.
Fine. You can stay in here
for the rest of the day, then.
Jude,
your father and I said no doll.
Okay, I am gonna count to three,
and if this door isn't open...
One...
Two...
Three.
What are you doing here?
Hey.
I have someone here
who wants to apologize.
Come on.
Hey.
Thank you for apologizing.
Okay.
Let's get you to bed, yeah?
Go brush your teeth.
Good boy.
You okay?
Not good.
I could've sworn I saw somebody
go into his room, and then...
You didn't.
It's fine.
Honestly, his pranks
are getting out of hand.
Yeah, but I thought
everything would be better
once we got out of the city.
I don't know what to do.
I just feel like
I'm letting you and Jude down.
You're not letting anyone down.
Please don't be sorry.
You'll feel better after some sleep.
Yeah.
- Good night.
- All right.
I understand that some of Jude's
recent behaviors would be upsetting.
But the doll clearly is providing him
with a safe outlet
lo process his trauma.
Now comes the hard part,
where he might try fo act out some more.
Act out?
Listen, what if we just
got rid of the doll?
How bad would that be?
I urge you to be patient,
and allow him to have his friend.
He's found a place with this doll
where he feels safe.
And the last thing we want fo do
is take that away.
I'll send you some links
with further information.
Okay. Sounds good.
Thanks, doc.
We'll speak to you soon, yeah?
Okay. Take care.
Perfect.
There you go. Nice.
Come on, Jude.
That's it.
One, and then move it on.
Perfect.
Hello, Jude.
What you got there?
Okay.
You thought of a name for him yet?
What is it?
Course it is.
You've scrubbed up well,
little man.
So, I see you've found yourself
a new family.
How're you doing,
little fella?
Just look at that expression
on his face.
It's like he's got a secret
that only he knows.
Do you ever notice that?
Can I help you?
Oh, hello there.
I was just looking for oz,
my daft dog.
We haven't seen him.
All right, never mind.
Pretty good idea
where he'll be, anyway.
Right, I'll be off.
You be good now.
Come on.
It's time to go inside.
You left Jude outside all alone?
I just left him for a second.
- What happened?
- I'm sorry.
I just saw it. It was just there.
- My god, Liza. What are you doing?
Jude?
"I'll always be with you"?
"They will be sorry."
Sorry.
I didn't know you were standing there.
Why are you wearing that?
Dinner's in 15.
No. It's just the three of us
for dinner tonight, Jude.
No, not tonight.
Does it really matter, Liza?
Your mum said no, mate.
So, I was thinking of inviting Liam out,
and the family.
Felt like maybe we could
use some company.
No? You wanna see your uncle Liam,
auntie Mary, and your cousins?
I think it'll be fun.
He's always a good laugh, isn't he?
I think he'd love
to get out of the city.
Not really guests.
They're family.
Yeah?
Your dad and I make the rules
in this house, not your doll.
Mm-mmm.
Eat it.
All right, come on.
Enough.
No, it's fine.
You can sit here until you decide
you can eat your food.
Just do as your mum says, please.
Look, I can handle this.
It's okay. It's fine.
You have work to do.
Well, if you won't talk to me,
will the doll?
That's because brahms is not a person.
He's not real.
He doesn't need any food.
You do.
The doll and his rules
do not run this house.
Fine.
Stay here all night, then.
What?
Jude.
Liza, what in the hell happened?
Look, I believe you,
I do.
It's just...
So, some scary drawings.
It's not really surprising, is it?
Considering what he's been through.
The drawing of the dog.
The dog?
There is no dog here.
There was one.
And others.
Sean, there was a drawing of Jude
standing over our dead bodies
and he was holding a gun.
So, you're saying he ripped pages
out of his book?
No, I...
I don't know what happened.
I just know that I want that doll
out of our house.
Look, you need to slow down.
I need to think about this.
No, I don't want it here.
I don't like what it's doing to Jude.
What?
I mean, all of this.
This is a lot for a little kid,
don't you think?
This isn't a light table,
for starters.
Are you asking me if I did this?
Somebody's done this.
You're the only person in here with him.
No! Something is happening to him.
And it started with that doll.
Fine. We'll get rid of the doll
in the morning, okay?
What are we gonna do
about them, brahms?
Oz! Where are you, boy?
Come here, oz.
Come here, boy.
Oh, oz.
Ah. Lovely.
I need that. Thank you.
Ready? Yeah.
Let's do it.
Morning, mister.
No.
Sean.
Jude!
Come on, buddy!
It's not funny. Jude!
I'll go this way.
- You head off that way.
- Okay.
We'll circle round.
We'll meet back at the house.
Jude!
Jude?
Jude.
Jude? Is that you?
Jude, what are you doing?
Jude, where are you?
This way, mommy.
Over here.
Come play with us, mommy.
Jude?
Jude.
I'm sorry I scared you.
We were just playing, mommy.
It's so good to hear your voice.
There you are.
Been looking all over for you.
Didn't you hear us calling?
No.
Jude. What the hell
are you doing in here? It's not safe.
I'm sorry, daddy.
Jude, he's...
You're talking.
Right, let's go.
We're not really supposed to be
in this part of the house.
Come on.
It's so nice to hear you talking.
Joseph, what happened in this house?
Uh, Jude, why don't you go
show brahms the music room?
Stay close, mate.
There was a family
that lived here a long time ago.
Had a son,
went a bit mad.
Killed a little girl.
Got burnt up in fire.
Wore a mask to hide it.
Lived inside the walls
of the house for 30 years.
Never came out.
The heelshires?
Yeah, the heelshires.
And?
And the parents committed suicide.
Drowned themselves.
It's a very sad story.
And the son?
Well, it all got a bit messy
after the parents had gone.
He killed a man, very nearly two others,
before he was killed himself.
But they're all dead and buried now.
What's the son's name?
His name was brahms.
Did you say brahms?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to keep it from you.
I just didn't think it'd ever come up.
Thank you for telling us.
Come on, Jude.
It's time to go home.
Hey, Joseph?
Did you ever find your dog?
Yes, I did.
I'm afraid oz was found
gutted in the forest.
I'm sorry to hear that.
So, your parents fell me
you've been talking again.
Is this your new friend brahms?
He seems like a very nice friend.
What are some of the things
you talk about?
He tells me all sorts of things.
Sometimes he tells me about
the other families he's lived with.
Oh, has he lived with a lot of families?
He wants to live with us now.
He was very angry that mommy and daddy
wanted to take him away.
Oh, and when brahms gets angry,
does he say he wants fo
hurt someone or something?
Is there something
he wants to tell your mum and dad?
Well, if Jude had something fo do
with the dog's death,
then this is a lof more serious
than we thought.
The doll might be enabling him
fo shift blame
for all the bad things that he might do.
I think it would be a good idea
for me fo see him face-to-face.
When do you think
you can bring him down to London?
We've got guests coming today,
but we'll bring him as soon as we can.
All right, then.
But I urge you, keep a close eye on him
in the meanwhile.
Jude! Everyone's here.
- Come on in, girls.
- All right.
- Make yourself at home.
- Thank you.
This is just fabulous!
I love it.
Hello.
Well, look.
There he is.
You remember your old uncle Liam,
don't you?
Hey.
What?
It's not my fault he's mental.
And who's this handsome chap?
Brahms.
Well, hello there, brahms.
Pleased to meet you.
Any friend of Jude's
is a friend of mine.
Okay, children,
why don't we go outside and play
while we all have a catch-up.
Yes.
There's nothing to do outside.
There's nature.
All right?
It's like a video game, but real.
Go, enjoy.
Come on, Jude.
Show them around.
- Maybe I should go with them.
- Oh, nonsense. They'll be fine.
Just stay close to the house, guys.
This is so cool.
Shut up.
I like your doll.
Thanks.
This place sucks.
There's nothing to do here.
We could play croquet.
I wanna play.
Come on.
Don't touch him, Sophie.
He's mental.
No, I'm not.
My parents say you talk to that doll,
like it's a real person.
Because you went crazy
when your mum got attacked.
And we're not supposed to notice.
Will!
But they know you're mental.
And I know you're mental.
And your stupid doll,
he's the most mental of all.
He's fine, Liza.
Have some wine.
It'll do him good to hang out
with some other children.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Ever since it happened,
I just...
I can't seem to relax.
Hey, you're with family now.
You don't have anything to worry about.
And will won't let anything happen.
Hey, you're breaking it!
Shut up, nutter.
Stop it, will!
Oh! You're sticking up
for your nutter boyfriend now.
Maybe I should just smash your doll.
Maybe that will make you normal again.
Don't.
We get to this party,
and we have literally
just walked in the door,
and his pants split right in the bum.
And not just a little tear,
the whole bum!
I'm going to tell mum!
She'll probably be happy.
Don't touch him.
Or what?
Or he'll make you wish
you never came here.
Did you buy him purple boxers?
I did.
Kinky.
Oh, it's good to see
that smile again, Liza.
That old smile of yours.
Give it back!
Nah, I don't think I will.
Give it back to her.
Oh! Now your boyfriend's mad.
Why don't you come get it
from me, mental?
I wouldn't worry
about this doll thing.
Will used to be obsessed
with this blanket.
Run, mental, run.
Stop it, will!
Obsessed.
Then one day I realized that it was
quite literally a security blanket.
And I think this doll could be
the same thing.
Come on, mental.
You shouldn't worry about it,
is what I'm saying.
Kids do all sorts of weird things.
They go through phases.
And then poof, it's gone.
- Oh, my god.
- What? What's going on?
Will!
- Easy, on three. One, two, three.
- Mind his head!
Slowly. Slowly.
Mary, help with his head, okay?
Will, I'm coming in.
Sophie, get in the front.
Sweetheart, why don't you drink
some of this? It'll help you sleep.
A nap will do you good.
Okay?
There you go.
Mommy.
Everything's okay.
He won't let me go.
He wants me to live in the big house
with him forever.
He said he'd kill you and daddy
if I didn't do it.
He said that?
When did he say that?
He says it all the time.
I can't control him anymore.
He keeps getting stronger.
Well...
No one's gonna hurt mommy and daddy.
And no one's gonna hurt you.
Okay?
Hey, Liza, it's me.
Um, we just saw the doctor.
I think will's gonna be okay.
So, I'll call you from the car.
All right.
I love you. Bye.
Not from around here,
are you?
I'm staying at the glennview estates.
Glennview?
Oh, you mean the heelshire place.
Christ, you couldn't pay me money
to stop there.
- You what?
- You don't know?
Whole family went completely mad
out there.
Something fo do with a son
living inside the walls for years.
You see, but that's not the only thing
that happened out there.
There were other tragedies before.
Back in the 50s, a kid killed
his own mother and brother,
convinced a doll was speaking to him.
And its still going on.
Last year, that city man
that bought it after the heelshires
went a bit mad and disappeared.
Never heard from again.
I saw him down the pub one time.
Old crazy Joe.
Crazy Joe?
That's what people called him, like.
His name were Joseph...
Oh, my god. Jude!
Jude!
Didn't have to be like this.
Joseph.
Is Jude okay?
Don't worry.
He's safe.
Safer now than he's probably
ever been in his life.
Why are you here?
I'm here because he wants me to be.
Who?
Brahms.
He doesn't like it like this,
but you've done it to yourself.
I just wanna know where my son is.
I will do anything you want.
Just give me my son.
I want you to listen!
He wants you to listen!
You asked me why I'm here.
It's the same reason that you are.
He called me.
He calls out to the ones that need him.
The damaged ones.
He looks inside you.
It was just a whisper...
At first,
when I first came here.
So quiet.
And he was in pieces when I found him,
broken.
And then the voice said...
Lo put him back together.
So I did.
Then I heard him, growing inside.
You must have heard it.
Jude sure has.
Oh, yeah.
I don't know what brahms is,
but you can stop this.
It's too late.
Brahms and Jude are gonna be one,
and it'll be beautiful.
Everybody thought that I was crazy.
They thought the heelshires
were crazy, but, no.
It's always been the doll.
Even before the house,
before the Davies, the ones before that.
I found all their old letters.
He knew that you were coming.
He knew your boy would find him.
That's why he told me to bury him.
They're always so curious, aren't they?
The little ones are like...
Like moths to a flame.
Joseph, where is my son?
I wanna see my son!
He's in the big house!
Jude!
Jude.
Jude?
Over here.
This way.
We're just over here.
Jude...
I know you don't wanna hurt anybody.
This isn't you, Jude.
Please, put him down.
It's going to be okay.
Can I hold brahms?
I used to hold you just like this.
Let's just put him down.
Hello, mommy.
Jude, put the gun down.
We're very angry.
You and daddy
have been getting in the way.
We're going to live here now...
Because you can't protect us.
Protect you from who?
That dog.
Will.
And those men from that night.
You're right.
We do need brahms to protect us.
It's too late.
You've given us no choice.
Goodbye, mommy.
I know brahms
is telling you what to say.
Which is why we need
to take him home with us.
Brahms needs to be
a member of our family.
And what kind of a family
doesn't need a mother?
Mom?
Jude.
What have you done?
Stay back.
It's me he'll punish.
I'm the one who didn't protect him.
No, no. Joseph,
brahms can't hurt you anymore.
You don't understand.
It will never be over.
It's gonna be all right, brahms.
- Mom! You're home.
- Yes. I missed you.
- I missed you too.
- Really?
- Perfect timing.
- Hey.
Hey, beautiful.
How was your day?
It was good.
I think we might sign that author
I was telling you about.
Yeah? Nice!
All righty.
Wait until you taste it,
because I'm pretty confident
that this might be
the greatest cog au vin
ever made upon english shores.
I'm not even joking.
There's a whole bottle of wine in here,
so I'm not sure if...
No, okay.
I will give you some.
- Thank you.
- All right.
This looks so good.
Thank you.
Just two or three hours of my day.
- Hmm?
- Nothing much.
Is it my turn tomorrow?
Yeah. Cheers.
Good night, my man.
You sleep tight.
I love you, sweetie.
Love you too.
Good night.
Good night, brahms.
I think we'll be happy here.
If they learn the rules.